All right.
좋아요
Are you excited to see how this goes?
어떻게 될지 기대돼요?
Let's give it a try.
한번 해 보죠
So in this next section, I create a string called pi which has within it the code to do this series
다음 섹션에서 파이 문자열을 생성합니다 그 코드 안에는 시리즈 1에서 3번째를 더하고 5번째를 더하고
one minus the third plus a fifth, minus the seventh plus a ninth.
7번째에 9번째를 더하죠
You can see that for yourself.
직접 보세요
Check how many mistakes.
몇 개 틀렸는지 봐요
And then it's going to do that 100 a million times.
그런 다음 100만 번 반복하죠
And really it's like 200 million times because it's you can see each of this.
2억 번은 들었을 거예요 전부 다 보이거든요
It's doing like two two elements in that series.
그 시리즈에서 두 가지 요소를 하는 거죠
So it's 200 million of this series.
이런 시리즈가 2억 개예요
And we'll see how close to pi it gets and then it will print the result.
파이에 얼마나 가까운지 보고 결과를 프린트할 거예요
So let's do that.
그렇게 하죠
I'm now going to do some some evil code, which of course we can do because we know exactly what we're
이제 악성 코드를 하겠습니다 물론 할 수 있죠 우리가 뭘 하는지 정확히 아니까요
doing.
하지만 누가 엑스라고 하면 약간 의심해야 해요
ExAC, of course, is the command that runs Python code as specified in a string.
ExAC은 파이썬 코드를 문자열에 명시된 대로 실행하는 명령어죠
And now you can see with some confidence this string is doing nothing to to evil.
이제 이 문자열이 악에게 아무 짓도 안 하는 걸 볼 수 있죠
It's just doing this series.
이 시리즈를 하면서요
But you should always double check any time someone gives you code that involves an exec to make sure
하지만 임원이 관련된 코드를 줄 땐 항상 다시 확인해야 합니다 파일
there's no funny business with your file system, or making an internet connection or anything like
시스템에 문제가 있거나 인터넷 연결 같은 게 되지 않도록요
that.
하지만 이 경우에는 꽤 안전하니 한번 해 보죠
Exact pi.
정확한 파이예요
Let's see what happens.
어떻게 되나 보죠
So there's a pause.
잠시 멈췄어요
While Python thinks 200 million of those terms.
파이썬은 그중 2억 달러를 생각해요
And there we go.
다 됐어요
So let's see how well the Pi comes out after that.
파이가 어떻게 나오는지 보죠
3.14159265.
3번요 14159265년요
And that digit is wrong.
그 숫자가 틀렸어요
So 200 million of these terms don't get you that much.
Get in get 약관 2억 개로는 얼마 못 벌어요
Pi.
파이요
As you probably you may know, there are much better series that converge very quickly, but they are
아시겠지만, 빠르게 모이는 더 좋은 나열도 있어요 하지만 그것들은
a lot more code and a lot more gumph.
훨씬 더 코드가 많고 검프하죠
This is the benefit of being super simple to write, but slowly converging.
쓰기는 쉽지만 점차 집약되는 것의 장점이죠
So it took 8.5764 seconds for that to run.
8시간 걸렸어요 5764초 걸렸어요
There's a if you run this a few times, you'll see that that changes a fair amount because of other
이걸 몇 번 실행하면 꽤 많이 변하는 걸 볼 수 있어요 컴퓨터에서 다른 일들이
things going on on the machine.
벌어지고 있으니까요
And your machine is different to mine, but you get the general idea.
Get it의 기계는 제 것과 다르지만 대략적인 건 아시겠죠
Okay.
네
So I should be able to run optimize GPT pi, and it should stream out C plus plus code that will do
GPT 파이 최적화를 실행할 수 있어야 합니다 그러면 C++ 코드를
the same thing by sending that string as part of the user prompt to GPT four.
내보내는데 GPT4에 문자열을 보내 같은 일을 하죠
Oh, let's see what we get.
Get up, Get up, Get up! 뭐가 나올지 보죠
Uh, this is what I mentioned to you.
제가 말씀드린 게 이거예요
It puts this at the top of the file, which we then strip out before saving this to disk.
이걸 파일 상단에 놓습니다 디스크에 저장하기 전에 제거하죠
This is the method.
이게 방법이에요
Uh, not uh, you may or may not be a C plus plus guru, but, uh, regardless, from knowledge of similar
여러분이 C 플러스 구루일 수도 아닐 수도 있지만 어쨌든 비슷한 지식을 바탕으로 보면 이 앱도 같은
things, you can probably get a good handle on the fact that this is doing the same thing.
일을 한다는 사실을 잘 이해하실 수 있을 거예요.
Uh, and it's doing a similar number of calculations, similar number of terms, and it has written
비슷한 수의 계산을 하고 비슷한 수의 용어를 하고 여기에 파일을 작성했어요
a file here, optimized C plus plus.
최적화된 C 플러스 플러스
And there it is.
저기 있네요
You can see it all looks good.
다 좋아 보이죠
And it has included this package that needs to be included, which is because it uses a set precision
포함되어야 하는 이 패키지도 포함되어 있습니다. 왜냐하면 이것은 정밀 함수를 사용하니까요.
And if I discovered if I don't put that in the user prompt, then it doesn't include this package which
이걸 발견하면 사용자 프롬프트에 넣지 않으면 패키지를 포함하지 않아요 파열을
causes it to break.
유발하는 패키지죠
So there we go.
자, 됐어요
For whatever it's worth, we've given it the hint and it's done it.
어찌 됐든 우리가 힌트를 줬고 그게 해냈어요
Um, okay.
네
So look at this next cell.
다음 방을 보세요
So this next cell.
다음 감방이에요
You remember, if you do an exclamation mark in Jupyter, then it, uh, it will um, uh, it will run
기억하시겠지만 Jupyter에서 느낌표를 하면 그건 그걸 터미널 명령으로
that as a terminal command.
실행할 거예요
So what I'm doing here is a terminal command.
여기서 하는 건 터미널 명령이에요
Uh clang++.
클랭++요
Uh, and this particular statement is running optimized.
이 문장은 최적화되어 실행되고 있어요
It's doing a compile and then running that C plus plus code.
컴파일을 하고 C++ 코드를 실행하고 있어요
Um, and later we're going to use an even more optimized way of doing this.
나중에는 더 최적화된 방법을 사용할 거예요
But this this is a good for now for your computer.
하지만 이건 지금 컴퓨터에는 좋아요
You may want to Google what it will take to to compile.
컴파일에 뭐가 필요한지 구글에 검색해 보세요
Um, if you're using a mac, then you may need to um, Uh, at least open Xcode to make sure you've
맥을 사용한다면 적어도 Xcode를 열어서 최신 Xcode 도구들이 설치되었는지
got the latest Xcode tools installed so that you have the latest versions of compilers.
확인해야 합니다 최신 버전의 컴파일러가 있도록요
Um, but but regardless, a quick Google will tell you how you compile a C plus plus file.
어쨌든 구글에 검색하면 C 플러스 파일을 어떻게 컴파일하는지 알 수 있어요
Um, once you've changed this line to be an optimized C plus plus compile of the file optimized CPP,
이 라인을 최적화된 C++ 파일 최적화된 CPP의 컴파일로 바꾸고 나면 당연히
that is of course how you will run it.
그렇게 실행하게 되죠
So remember what we are looking to beat is 8.57 seconds.
8점을 넘어서야 한다는 걸 기억하세요 57초요
Let's see how GPT four zero how its code has done.
GPT 40 코드가 어떻게 작동하는지 보죠
Here we go.
시작할게요
And it's got the same answer I should imagine 658 at least to within.
대답은 같아요 적어도 658개 안쪽으로요
Yes.
네
Looks like it.
그런 것 같아요
I mean you'd expect some.
예상했던 대로예요
Oh no it's there's not even any rounding differences.
아뇨, 반반되는 것도 없어요
It looks like it's exactly right.
딱 맞는 것 같아요
And it's in a fraction of the time 0.21.
시간의 0분의 1밖에 안 돼요 21살요
Uh, so it is clearly, uh, um, somewhere between 10 and 100 times faster.
그러니까 확실히 10배에서 100배 정도 빨라요
You'll find later, when we optimize further, we can do even better than this.
나중에 최적화하면 더 좋아질 거예요
But.
하지만요
But with these flags, that is what we get.
하지만 이 깃발로 그걸 얻게 되죠 get it get it
It's pretty impressive.
정말 인상적이에요
We've just built something that can do a conversion of code from Python to C plus plus and run it many
파이썬 에서 C++로 코드를 변환할 수 있는 것을 빌드했습니다 그리고 훨씬 빠르게
times faster.
실행할 수 있죠
Let's see how Claude does.
클로드는 어떤지 보죠
Well, let's just quickly compare the code.
코드를 빨리 비교해보죠
The code looks pretty similar to me.
코드가 비슷해 보여요
Uh, you will find, if you look at it, that there are some subtle differences.
자세히 보시면 미묘한 차이가 있어요
For example, there is this stuff here, um, which is to do with, uh.
예를 들어 여기 이런 게 있어요
Well, I am not a C plus plus expert, although I did code in C plus plus some time ago, 1 or 2 years
전 C 플러스 전문가가 아닙니다 1, 2년 전에 C 플러스 코딩은 해봤지만요
Uh, but, uh, sadly, that is all swapped out in my mind.
하지만 안타깝게도 제 머릿속에선 다 바뀌었어요
Uh, and I would certainly never have got to this level of expertise.
이 정도 전문 지식은 절대 못 얻었을 거예요
It's putting in, I believe, various hints to suggest that things can be parallelized, but I sort
병렬화될 수 있다는 걸 암시하는 다양한 힌트를 넣고 있는 것 같아요 하지만 이런
of suspect with some of this stuff the compiler would apply that anyway in both cases, but we will
것과 관련해 제 생각엔 컴파일러가 두 경우 모두 적용할 것 같아요 두고 보죠
see.
이게 실제로 차이를 만드는지 보죠 같은 명령을 실행하면서요
Uh, sorry, did I run that?
죄송해요, 제가 그랬나요?
Let's try that again.
다시 해 보죠
Here we go.
시작할게요
And this is the answer that we got.
이게 그 답이에요
Um, and it looks like, um, I think we may have to go back and do.
아무래도 다시 돌아가서 작업해야 할 것 같아요
Oh, no.
안 돼요
Here we go.
시작할게요
Sorry.
미안해요
This was Gpg's version, so GPT was 0.2121.
이건 Gpg 버전이었어요 GPT는 0이었죠 2121요
And here I've jumped ahead.
여기서 앞서갔죠
That's why I'm getting confused.
그래서 헷갈리는 거예요
Sorry.
미안해요
Let's go back up again.
다시 올라가죠
Uh, I'm going to have to write this down 0.2131 is GPT version and Claude's Version is in 0.2121.
0번 적어 둘게요 2131은 GPT 버전이고 클로드 버전은 0이에요 2121요
So Claude was a hair faster than GPT.
클로드는 GPT보다 약간 빨랐어요
But I gotta tell you, this is within in error bars.
하지만 이건 에러바 안에 있어요
If you run this a few times, it will vary by at least that amount.
몇 번 실행하면 그 정도까지 차이가 나요
So basically they've both produced code which when running on the machine, uh, has run at the same
기본적으로 둘 다 코드를 만들었어요 컴퓨터에서 실행될 때 같은 속도로 실행되는 코드요
speed.
실제 컴파일된 머신 코드는 두 경우 모두 동일할 것 같아요
Um, which is what you would expect for a fairly simple problem.
아주 간단한 문제니까 당연한 결과죠
Uh, so both GPT four and Claude have crushed it with a well optimized solution to this, uh, Python
GPT4와 클로드는 파이를 생성하기 위한 파이썬 코드의 최적화된 솔루션으로
code to generate pi.
잘 해냈죠
Uh, but, um, uh, although, as I'll say, GPT four did need a few more hints than Claude, but they
하지만 GPT 4는 클로드보다 힌트가 더 필요했지만 둘 다 휴식 시간이
both got there after the break.
끝나고 도착했어요
We're going to move to a harder problem, much harder code to see how they can optimize.
더 어려운 문제로 넘어가겠습니다 훨씬 어려운 코드요 어떻게 최적화할 수 있는지 보기 위해서요
I will see you in the next video.
그럼 다음 영상에서 만나요